杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 除了表面水平的建筑静态网站,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Beyond just
the surface level building static sites,
盖茨比有许多先进的特点。
Gatsby has tons of advanced features.
今天我们要讨论的内容之一就是主题和
So one of the things that we're gonna
talk about today is theming and
主题作文。
theme composition.
你可以编写捆绑的功能和样式
You can write up bundled functionality and
styles and
的插件和配置，把它们放到一个主题中，然后安装
plugins and configuration for Gatsby, put
that into a theme and then install that
就像插件一样，你会得到所有的功能。
into a site as if it was a plugin,
and you'll get all that functionality.
然后你可以在这个主题旁边安装另一个主题,
Then you can install another
theme next to that theme,
他们只是一起工作。
and they just work with each other.
他们不是在竞争，他们不会为了某些事情而争吵。
They're not competing,
they're not gonna, fight over things.
这确实需要很好地构建你们的主题但我们今天就要这么做,
That does require building your themes
well, but we're gonna do that today,
所以你不用担心。
so don't you worry about that.
您还可以构建自定义数据源。
You can also build custom data sources.
你可以从任何地方获得数据，如果你有一个内部的 API，你可以构建
You can get data from anywhere, if you've
got an in house API, you can build
一个 Gatsby 源代码插件，它将把这个插件加入到 GraphQL API 中。
a Gatsby source plugin that will pull that
in and make it part of the GraphQL API.
我们不会建立一个自定义的数据源，但是
We're not gonna build
a custom data source but
我们将执行模式定制。
we are going to do Schema customization.
因此，这涵盖了采购数据的大部分基本内容。
So that covers most of
the basics of sourcing data.
我们要结合构建时间和运行时间数据
We're gonna combine build time and
run time data so
你可以得到大量的数据，任何不经常变化的数据。
you can get a lot of the data,
anything that doesn't change frequently.
在构建的时候把它们放在一起，这样网站就有了可用的
Put it together at build time, so
that the site has that available and
将离线工作，并加载非常迅速。
will work offline and loads very quickly.
然后事情经常改变，如果你有库存，或者
And then things that change frequently
like if you've got inventory, or
如果你运行类似股票应用程序的东西
if you were running
something like a stock app
每隔几秒钟就要改变一次价格。
that needed to change prices
every couple of seconds.
你不可能每隔几秒钟就重建你的网站。
You wouldn't be able to rebuild
your site every couple of seconds.
所以你可以得到客户端，只是更新，你可以做到这一点与任何
So you can get that client side and
just update and you can do that with any
你想要的骨骼模式，旋转器，随便什么。
pattern that you want skeleton patterns,
spinners, whatever.
架构自定义和自定义数据类型允许您克服一些问题。
Schema customization and custom data types
allows you to overcome a couple problems.
一种是如果数据是空的，如果您正在使用文件系统和
One is if the data is empty,
like if you're using the file system and
没有文件，盖茨比会说你想念这个领域。
there are no files, Gatsby would
say you're missing this field.
因为没有数据来证明这个字段的存在。
Because there was no data
to make that field exist.
通过创建自定义数据类型，我们可以避免这些错误。
By creating custom data types
we can avoid those errors.
所以我们实际上得到了空的设置回来，你可以这样做。
So we actually get empty sets back and
you can do things like.
在高级情况下，你可以说我想要一个页面。
In advanced cases,
you could say I wanna have a page.
我的页面可能来自 Markdown。
And my page could come from Markdown.
或者它可能来自 WordPress，或者它可能来自 Contentful 或
Or it could come from WordPress, or
it could come from Contentful or
任何其他地方，但我只是想查询页面。
any other number of places,
but I just wanna query pages.
因此，通过模式定制和自定义数据类型，您可以
So with schema customization and
custom data types, you can
实际上把所有这些数据源的数据放到一个桶里。
actually pull data from all of those
sources and put them into one bucket.
我们今天不讨论这个。
We're not gonna get into that today.
但是，我们将进入单一源的模式定制。
But we are gonna get into schema
customization for a single source.
实际上这里潜在的信息是，任何反应可以做的事情,
And really the the underlying message
here is that anything that React can do,
盖茨比最有可能处理好。
Gatsby can most likely handle.
说到底，《了不起的盖茨比》是一个不错的提供 React 应用程序的软件包
Gatsby is, at the end of the day, a nice
package for serving React apps, which
这意味着 React 应用只是 React 应用，你可以做几乎所有相同的事情。
means that React apps are just React apps
you can do almost all of the same things.
这里几乎没有什么限制，几乎所有这些地方都有逃生舱口
There are very few restrictions and almost
all of those have escape hatches and
我们今天会看看其中的一些工作。
controls and
we'll look at some of that works today.